### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# JOO YOUNG KIM MARCH 16, 2020

#### **PERSONAL INFORMATION:**

Work Home

Address: 222 Wangsimni-ro Address: 459-18 Deongneung-ro

Seongdong-gu, SEOUL 04763 Nowon-gu, Seoul 01769

Email: jykim1026@hanyang.ac.kr

Website: jooyoungkim.info

Citizenship: Republic of Korea

PhD candidate and Technical Research Personnel in the Biomedical Engineering Department at Hanyang University, South Korea.

I work with Professor In Young Kim in the Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.

I completed my B.S. in Biomedical Engineering at Hanyang University and can handle most bio-signals and medical images. In particular, I can design the whole systems for electrical bio-signals, including hardware design, firmware coding and analysis.

Through the analysis of bio-signals and medical images, I have become interested in computer science and have a need for related research. So, we created an A.I. team in the lab and I am currently working on this team, doing CNN and RNN based research.

## **EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL APPOINTMENTS**

**EDUCATION:** 

2016-Present Ph.D. candidate, Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Supervisor: Dr. In Young Kim

2012-2016 B.Sc. Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

HONORS, AWARDS:

2017 Best Paper Award The Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering

## **RESEARCH**

#### **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:**

2016-Present Graduate Research Assistant, A.I. team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.,

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2015-2016 Undergraduate Research Intern, Hearing team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.,

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2017-Present Research Assistant, Smart Healthcare & Device Research Center,

Samsung Medical Center, Seoul, Korea

#### MAJOR AREAS OF RESEARCH INTEREST

Machine learning and deep learning in medical image

Biomedical engineering, Computer science, Electrical engineering

#### **PUBLICATIONS:**

## REFEREED JOURNAL ARTICLES: \* lead author; ^ co-author

- 1. <u>Kim, J. Y.\*</u>, Ro, K., You, S., Nam, B. R., Yook, S., Park, H. S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2019). Development of an automatic muscle atrophy measuring algorithm to calculate the ratio of supraspinatus in supraspinous fossa using deep learning. *Computer methods and programs in biomedicine*, 182, 105063.
- Kim, J. Y.\*, Nam, K. W., Lee, J. C., Hwang, J. H., Jang, D. P., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Scalp tapping-based protocol for adjusting the parameters of binaural hearing aids. *Biomedical Signal Processing and Control*, 45, 91-97.
- 3. Kim, D. Y., Kwon, J., Kim, J. Y., Cha, H. S., Kim, Y. W., Kim, I. Y., & Im, C. H. (2018). New Method for Pure-Tone Audiometry Using Electrooculogram: A Proof-of-Concept Study. *Sensors*, 18(11), 3651.
- 4. So, S., You, S. M., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, An, H. J., Cho, B. H., Yook, S., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Development of Age Classification Deep Learning Algorithm Using Korean Speech. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 39(2), 63-68.
- 5. <u>Kim, J.\*</u>, Lee, S., Kim, K., Cho, K., You, S., So, S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2017). Development of Bone Metastasis Detection Algorithm on Abdominal Computed Tomography Image using Pixel Wise Fully Convolutional Network. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 38(6), 321-329.